Guide to the Derrick A. Bell, Jr. Papers MC.138
New York University Archives
- SERIES I: CORRESPONDENCE, 1959 - 1992 (Boxes 1-20)
  - Correspondence, Feb 1986 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, chronological, Feb 1986 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Mar 1986 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Apr 1986 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, Apr 1986 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, May 1986 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    Barcode:31142042274954
  - Correspondence, chronological, Jun 1986-Aug 1986 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, chronological, Sep 1986 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, chronological, Oct 1986 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, chronological, Nov 1986 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, chronological, Dec 1986 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, chronological, Dec 1986 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1987 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Feb 1987 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Mar 1987 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Apr 1987 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, May 1987 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Homer Clay RESTRICTED, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Jun 1987 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Jul 1987 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Aug 1987 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Sep 1987 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, Sep 1987 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, outgoing, Sep 1987 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Oct 1987 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Barcode:31142042274962
  - Correspondence, incoming, Oct 1987 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Oct 1987 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Nov 1987 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Nov 1987 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Dec 1987 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, incoming, Dec 1987 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Dec 1987 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (protest announcement), 1987-1989 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (press clippings), 1987-1988 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence (press clippings), 1987-1989 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, outgoing A-G, 1987-1991 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - National Bar Assn. certificate, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence (press clippings), 1988-1989 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Resignation, 1988-1990 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, incoming - A-G, 1988-1991 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, incoming - A-G, 1988-1991 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, incoming - H-P, 1988-1991 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, incoming - H-P, 1988-1991 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, incoming - R-Z, 1988-1991 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Barcode:31142042274970
  - Correspondence, incoming - R-Z, 1988-1991 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, memos, 1988-1991 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Published letters, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - vita, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Harvard Univ., 1989-1991 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Resignation, Harvard Univ., 1990 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Bill Cosby Show, 1990-1991 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, N.Y.U., 1991 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Ford Foundation grant, 1991-1992 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Telephone message forms, Jun 1989-Jan 1990 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Telephone message forms, Jan 1990-Nov 1990 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Telephone message forms, Apr 1990-Jun 1991 (Box 20, Folder 14)
- SERIES II: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1960 - 1992 (Boxes 21-29)
  - Miscellaneous speeches, 1960s (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Barcode:31142042274988
  - Miscellaneous speeches, 1960s (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous speaking information, 1960s (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - NAACP Conference (Milwaukee), Oct 1963 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - "Problems of De Facto School Desegregation in the North", May 1965 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Cooperative Program in Political Education, Stillman College, May 1967 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - "The Federal Government's Interest in Equal Health Opportunity" (Pittsburgh), Jun 1967 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Civil Rights Orientation Program (Baltimore), Sep 1967 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - NAACP (Branch) State Conference (Durham, NC), Nov 1967 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - "National Purpose and the Need for Community" by Lisle C. Carter, Jr. (5th HEW Forum, Washington, D.C.), Jan 1968 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Law Day USA (Univ. Southern Cal.), Apr 1968 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - California Federal Bar Meeting (San Diego), May 1968 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Long-Range Planning/Integration (Stockton), Sep 1968 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - "The Western Center on Law and Poverty: Is it a Bird? Is it a Plane?", Oct 1968 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Speeches/Writings - Race Relations, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Speeches/Writings - "The Western Center on Law and Poverty", 1968 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - "The Nature of Violence in Contemporary Society", Mar 1969 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - "Welfare Rights and Professional Commitment: An Invitation to Join the Revolution" (National Conference on Social Welfare, Columbus, OH), May 1969 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - "The Role of the Courts in the Correction of Social Injustice" (National Conference of Social Welfare), May 1969 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - "Black Worth in a White Land" (Pittsburgh), Oct 1969 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Harvard School Lecture Materials, Oct 1969 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - School Lunch Conference (Washington, DC), Dec 1969 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - School Lunch Conference (Washington, DC), undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - School Lunch Conference (Washington, DC), Dec 1969 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - School Lunch Conference (Washington, DC), Dec 1969 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1960s (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - "The New Double Standard" (Town Hall of California), Sep 1969 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - "Legal Resources for Solving Current Urban Problems" (SUNY-Buffalo Law School), Sep 1970 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Senior Seminar in Foreign Policy, Oct 1970 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Visiting Black Law Professionals Symposium, Oct 1970 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Minority Law Teachers Conference - Ad Hoc Committee, 1970-1974 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Book review, "Law, Lawyers, and Social Change", 1971 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Speeches/Writings - Miscellaneous Speaking Requests, Sep 1971-Mar 1972 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - "Mother's Sons", Mar 1972 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Commentary on Pres. Nixon's Reelection, Oct 1972 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Letter to editor re: " Integration", Oct 1972 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - "A Triumphant Story" (Appleton Chapel), Oct 1972 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Black American Law Students Association, Feb 1973 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - "Minority Admissions Programs: Will they Help or Harm White Students?", 1973 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - "Daily Prayers", Jan 1974 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - "Law School Exams and Minority Group Students", May 1974 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - "The DeFunis Case: The Price of Racial Equality", May 1974 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - "School Desegregation: Constitutional Right or Obsolete Policy?", May 1974 (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - Black Student Orientation Dinner (Harvard), Sep 1974 (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - Minority Law Teachers Conference, Sep 1974 (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - Minority Law Teachers Conference, Sep 1974 (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - "Talk to First Year Students re: Exams", Dec 1974 (Box 21, Folder 47)
  - Response to Nathan Glazer's comment on Affirmative Discrimination, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - "The Black Lawyer as Law Teacher", 1974 (Box 21, Folder 49)
  - Review of "The Case for Black Reparations", 1974 (Box 21, Folder 50)
  - "The Real Cost of Racial Equality", 1974 (Box 21, Folder 51)
  - Minority Law Teachers Conference, 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Barcode:31142042274996
  - "Law and Contemporary Problems" (Duke article), 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - "The Friendly Enemies of Brown", 1975 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - "Desegregation and Public Education" (Boston), Apr 1975 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Univ. of Washington, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - "Make Black Schools Magnet; Equal to Best in the System" (Boston), Aug 1975 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - "The Client or the Cause: Ethical Questions in Professional Responsibility", Oct 1975 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - "Alternatives to School Integration: The School Systems' Role" (Cleveland), Oct 1975 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - "Will We Ever Integrate the Public Schools?" (Biloxi, Miss.), Nov 1975 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - "5-6-7-8, Who Do We Appreciate?" (Cambridge, MA), Nov 1975 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Racism: Chinese-Americans/Ko-Jen Tung, Dec 1975 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - "Racial Balance in Public Schools" (Kent State Univ.), Dec 1975 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - "A Matter of Tactics" (Boston), Dec 1975 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - "Alternative Remedies Under Brown", 1976 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Letter to Editor - School Desegregation, Jan 1976 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - "Bicentennial Dangers and Black Civil Rights", Feb 1976 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Leverett House Comments, Mar 1976 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - "Serving Two Masters: Integration Ideals in School Desegregation Litigation", Mar 1976 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - "Racial Remediation: An Historical Perspective...", Apr 1976 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - "Major Desegregation Cases: A Status Report" ("Of Leverage Lost" ), Apr 1976 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - "Remarks at RNA", May 1976 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - "Is Brown Obsolete? Yes!", May 1976-Jun 1976 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - "Where We Are: Another Point of View", Jun 1976 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - "Busing: A Rhetorical Dilemma for Committed Integrationists", Jun 1976 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - "Providing Equitable Educational Opportunity: State Silence and the Promise of Brown", Sep 1976 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - "Dr. DuBois and the Integrated-Separate School Dilemma Today", Oct 1976 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - "Report of Conference of Minority Administrators and Law Teachers", Nov 1976 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Comment, "Processes of Identification and Aggression in Racial Conflict" (Boston), Nov 1976 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - BUILD Symposium, Nov 1976 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - "Disaster by Decree", 1977 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - "Equal Employment Law and the Continuing Need for Self-Help", 1977 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - "The Role for the Church in the Education of Poor Black Children", Jan 1977 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - "The Theory of Racial Remediants", Jan 1977 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - "A Civil Rights Suit Against a Law Firm", 1977 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - "Weighing the Landmark Reverse Discrimination Case", Sep 1977 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - "The High Price of Non-Representation", Sep 1977 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - "N.Y. Looters Story: Disgust for all those who fail to make it", Sep 1977 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - "The Racial Imperative in American Law", Oct 1977 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - "The Legacy of W.E.B. DuBois: A Rational Model for Achieving Public School Equity for American's Black Children", Oct 1977 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - "The Mirage of Metropolitan School Remedies", 1977-1978 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Barcode:31142042275001
  - Miscellaneous articles and comments, 1977-1978 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - "Dependent Status" (fiction), 1977-1979 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - "Black Labor and the American Legal System" by Herbert Hill, book review, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - "Civil Rights Commitment and the Challenge of Changing Conditions in Urban School Cases", 1978 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - "The Community Role in Education of Poor Black Children", 1978 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - "The Referendum: Democracy's Barrier to Racial Equality", 1978 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - "The School Integration Battle: Leaders and Losses in 25 years", 1978 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - "The Wechslarian Question Revived", 1978 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - "Conformity and Social Reform in the People's Republic", Feb 1978 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - "Viewing the American Ideal from Red China", Mar 1978 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - "Doing the State Some Service: Paul Robeson and the Civil Rights Movement", Apr 1978 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - "The Curse of Brown on Blacks", 1978 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - "The Hidden Race-Class Conflict in the Bakke Litigation", Jun 1978 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - "Court Ruling on Bakke: A Chance to Help Everyone", Jul 1978 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - "The Years Beyond Bakke's Case", Jul 1978 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Introduction to Dr. Vincent Harding, Oct 1978 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - "Did Blacks Lose Brown?", Oct 1978 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - "Book review", 1979 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Brown, Tony (Journal), 1979 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - "Awakening After Bakke", 1979 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - "The Bakke Decision: Who Won? Who Lost?", 1979 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Teachers College Conference, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Los Angeles Dinner on School Desegregation, Feb 1979 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Morning Prayers, Feb 1979 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - "Black Schools: A Current Need with a Historic Rationale" (June, 1979), May 1979 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - "Diagnosis, diagnosis: But Where is the Cure?", May 1979 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - "Supreme Court on Desegregation: 25 Years Later" by Tony Brown, May 1979 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Symposium: Biracial Education, Jul 1979 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - "A Gift of Time", Oct 1979 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Shades of Brown: 2nd edition, Teachers Manual, 1979-1980 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Shades of Brown - symposium manuscript, 1979-1980 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Shades of Brown, 1979-1980 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous speeches and unpublished writings, 1979-1981 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - "Black Lawyer Fights Uphill Battle", 1980 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Civil Rights - Leading Cases, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - "Front told Desegregation Stand 'Right", 1980 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - "Minorities Hurt by Integration..." (L.A. Times), 1980 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - "Numerical Racial Balance Wrong..." (Oregonian), 1980 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - "Prof. Bell Named U. of Oregon Law Dean", 1980 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - "Rights Activist Shifts His Stance" (L.A. Times), 1980 (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - Speeches/Writings - miscellaneous, 1980s (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - "Current Dilemmas in Law School Administration", Mar 1980 (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Statement, Mar 1980 (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - "A Reassessment of Racial-Balance Remedies" (Microfiche card included), Apr 1980 (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - "Discrimination: Current Constitutional and Statutory Issues", Apr 1980 (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - "School Desegregation in 1980: Questions and Answers", May 1980 (Box 23, Folder 47)
  - "Responsibility and Joy", May 1980 (Box 23, Folder 48)
  - "Black Schools an Effective Desegregation Remedy", May 1980 (Box 23, Folder 49)
  - "The Moral Dilemma of Middle Class Educational Reformers", Jun 1980-Jul 1980 (Box 23, Folder 50)
  - "Transitions and Trespasses in a Professional Career", Sep 1981 (Box 23, Folder 51)
  - National Conference of Black Lawyers, Sep 1980 (Box 23, Folder 52)
  - "Symposium: Race Relations in the '80s: Affirmative Action in Benign Neglect", Nov 1980 (Box 23, Folder 53)
  - "Reagan and Blacks' Rights", Nov 1980 (Box 23, Folder 54)
  - Speeches and writings - news features, 1980-1982 (Box 23, Folder 55)
  - Candid Comments on the Oregon Law School, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Barcode:31142042275019
  - Review of books edited by D.A.B., 1981 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - "The Dialectics of School Desegregation" (Alabama Law Review), 1981 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - "Law School Dean Bell Man of Principle", 1981 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - "Law Dean Sees Difficulty in Harassment Cases", 1981 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - "Panelists Cite Progress By Blacks", 1981 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - "School Desegregation: The Alchemy of Post-Brown Liberals", 1981 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - "U.O. Law Dean Welcomes Debate", 1981 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Ninth Circuit Conference, Jan 1981 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - "B.S.U. Reception for Dean Derrick Bell", Jan 1981 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Meeting with student body, Jan 1981 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - "U. Of Oregon Reception Welcoming Dean Bell to School", Jan 1981 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Feb 1981 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Speech - Lane County Lawyers Brunch, Mar 1981 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Black Law Students Assn.: Mideast Regional Conference, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - "Private Laws and Public Judges", Apr 1981 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - "The Joys of Voluntary Challenge", Apr 1981 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - USA District Court Judges' Luncheon, Apr 1981 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - "Achievers and Achievements", Apr 1981 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Willamette Valley Chapter/Society of Professional Journalists, Apr 1981 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Douglas County Bar Assn., Apr 1981 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Dalles Rotary Banquet, May 1981 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Univ. Connecticut School of Law Commencement, May 1981 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - "Involuntary Career Challenges and the Equality Possibility", May 1981 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - "The Moral Obligations in Race-Sex Drafting", May 1981 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Oregon Council of School Board Attorneys, May 1981 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Oregon Council of School Attorneys, May 1981 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - "America: the World's Best Hope for Peace", May 1981 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Oregon Older Woman's Caucus, May 1981 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Unity Day, Jun 1981 (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - "Milestones, Marathons and Maybe Miracles", Jun 1981 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - 11th Year Anniversary Banquet - Westminster Presbyterian Church, Jun 1981 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - Joint Center for Political Studies, Jun 1981 (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - American College of Trial Lawyers, Jul 1981 (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - "Legal Education of the Third World", Jul 1981 (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Upward Bound Commencement, Aug 1981 (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - First Year Students, Aug 1981 (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - Meeting with 2nd and 3rd Year Students, Sep 1981 (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Harvard Law School Assn.; Oregon State Bar Meeting, Sep 1981 (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - Vancouver, B.C. - trip with Charles Smith, Sep 1981 (Box 24, Folder 40)
  - "Racial Isolation: Designing Strategies Beyond Racial Balance", Sep 1981 (Box 24, Folder 41)
  - National Committee of School Boards, Sep 1981 (Box 24, Folder 42)
  - School Desegregation Conference, Sep 1981 (Box 24, Folder 43)
  - "The Government as Scapegoat", Oct 1981 (Box 24, Folder 44)
  - Northwest Christian College, Oct 1981 (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - "The Lord, the Law, and the Education of Black Folks", Oct 1981 (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - "A Pre-game Status Report on your Alma Mater - or Saturday Morning Fever", Oct 1981 (Box 24, Folder 47)
  - "The Minority Admissions Debate: Still Viable After All These Years", Oct 1981 (Box 24, Folder 48)
  - May Day Panel, Oct 1981 (Box 24, Folder 49)
  - Moot Court, Nov 1981 (Box 24, Folder 50)
  - "Affirmative Action in the 1980s", Nov 1981 (Box 24, Folder 51)
  - Governor's Affirmative Action Conference, Nov 1981 (Box 24, Folder 52)
  - "The Origins of the Problem", Nov 1981 (Box 24, Folder 53)
  - Class lecture: American Legal Biography; the Continuing American Dilemma, Nov 1981 (Box 24, Folder 54)
  - Urban Caucus of the NEA, Dec 1981 (Box 24, Folder 55)
  - Scoles dinner, Dec 1981 (Box 24, Folder 56)
  - "The Talented Tenth in the Terrible '80s", Dec 1981 (Box 24, Folder 57)
  - "American Law's Black Hopes", Dec 1981 (Box 24, Folder 58)
  - "A Media Spotlight Shines ....", 1982 (Box 24, Folder 59)
  - "An Activist Makes Waves ....", 1982 (Box 24, Folder 60)
  - "Black Plight", 1982 (Box 24, Folder 61)
  - "Dean Bell Likes Balancing on the Cutting Edge of Change", 1982 (Box 24, Folder 62)
  - "Law School Dean Attacks 'Myopia' of White Voters", 1982 (Box 24, Folder 63)
  - "Lawyer Glut: Law Schools Enjoy Bumper Crop....", 1982 (Box 24, Folder 64)
  - "Legal Causes Concern Dean Derrick Bell", 1982 (Box 24, Folder 65)
  - "Memorials do not match Morse Legacy", 1982 (Box 24, Folder 66)
  - News Features, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 67)
  - "Portland, the Law, and Dean Bell", 1982 (Box 24, Folder 68)
  - "State's treatment of blacks criticized", 1982 (Box 24, Folder 69)
  - "U.O. Dean cites lag in minority gains", 1982 (Box 24, Folder 70)
  - Foreword from Civil Rights Issue/Oregon Law Review, May 1982 (Box 24, Folder 71)
  - "Unlikely Heroes" (book review, Yale Law Journal), 1982 (Box 24, Folder 72)
  - "An Activist Makes Waves at Oregon's Law School" by Lisa Stryker, Western Law Journal, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 73)
  - "A New American Justice" (book review, Harvard Law Review), 1982 (Box 24, Folder 74)
  - "Assurance in a world of uncertainty", Jan 1982 (Box 24, Folder 75)
  - ABA Dean's Workshop (Chicago), Jan 1982 (Box 24, Folder 76)
  - "Civil Rights and Current Economic Development", Jan 1982 (Box 24, Folder 77)
  - Introduction, Indian Law Conference, Feb 1982 (Box 24, Folder 78)
  - Oregon State Bar Examination, Feb 1982 (Box 24, Folder 79)
  - "The Many Dimensions of Merit Hiring", Feb 1982 (Box 24, Folder 80)
  - MLSA (sic), Mar 1982 (Box 24, Folder 81)
  - "A Word About Wayne Morse", Mar 1982 (Box 24, Folder 82)
  - Benton Co. Bar Assn., Mar 1982 (Box 24, Folder 83)
  - "The Trouble With Moses", Mar 1982 (Box 24, Folder 84)
  - "The School Desegregation Issue is Still with Us", Apr 1982 (Box 24, Folder 85)
  - Oregon Symposium on Court Reorganization, Apr 1982 (Box 24, Folder 86)
  - Oregon Assembly for Black Affairs, Apr 1982 (Box 24, Folder 87)
  - Law Day - Downtown Lions (Portland), Apr 1982 (Box 24, Folder 88)
  - Ruffin portrait Dedication, May 1982 (Box 24, Folder 89)
  - "American Transition" (Seattle), May 1982 (Box 24, Folder 90)
  - Mini-Intern Program, Lane Co. Medical society, May 1982 (Box 24, Folder 91)
  - "The business of Law School", May 1982 (Box 24, Folder 92)
  - Portland City Club, Jul 1982 (Box 24, Folder 93)
  - National Judicial College (Eugene), Jul 1982 (Box 24, Folder 94)
  - Eugene Rotary, Jul 1982 (Box 24, Folder 95)
  - "Flexibility the Key to Improving Blacks' Education", Jul 1982 (Box 24, Folder 96)
  - "The Last Temptation of Brown", Jul 1982 (Box 24, Folder 97)
  - ABA Annual Meeting, Aug 1982 (Box 24, Folder 98)
  - ABA Law Student Division, Aug 1982 (Box 24, Folder 99)
  - "The Boycott at Harvard: Should Teaching be Color-blind?", undated (Box 24, Folder 100)
  - "Law School's Crossroads", Aug 1982 (Box 24, Folder 101)
  - Univ. Oregon Black Alumni Reunion, Aug 1982 (Box 24, Folder 102)
  - "A Question of Credentials", Sep 1982 (Box 24, Folder 103)
  - "Dean Bell Says Intent Being Misconstrued", Sep 1982 (Box 24, Folder 104)
  - "The Law Student as Slave", Oct 1982 (Box 24, Folder 105)
  - "Tenure in Retrospect", Oct 1982 (Box 24, Folder 106)
  - Notes for Mr. Stan Turner's AP Amer. Hist. Class, Oct 1982 (Box 24, Folder 107)
  - "Monitoring the Dr. Do-Goods", Oct 1982 (Box 24, Folder 108)
  - "Bell Reiterates Stand, Says Problem Real", Dec 1982 (Box 24, Folder 109)
  - Notre Dame Law School - BALSA (did not participate), Dec 1982 (Box 24, Folder 110)
  - Peyton Award Luncheon (Portland), Dec 1982 (Box 24, Folder 111)
  - Clackamas Co. Bar Assn., Dec 1982 (Box 24, Folder 112)
  - Miscellaneous talks, speeches, 1982-1983 (Box 24, Folder 113)
    Barcode:
  - Conversation, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Barcode:31142042275027
  - "Rebel without a Pause", 1983 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - "Rebel within the Law", 1983 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - "A School Desegregation Post-Mortem" (book review), 1983 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - "Time for the Teachers: Putting Educators Back into the Brown Remedy", undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - AALS Annual Meeting (Cincinnati), Jan 1983 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Santa Monica Junior College, Jan 1983 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Tri-County Affirmative Action (Portland), Jan 1983 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - "Looking to the Lighthouse of Oregon Law", Jan 1983 (Box 25, Folder 9)